ElCid Wang

SENIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER

CONTACT

elcidwang@gmail.com

Beijing,China •

bachtothefuture.com

linkedin.com/in/shuai-wang-877a432b1/

SELF DESCRIPTION

Have been working in the field of web development for over six years, possessing a solid programming foundation and excellent coding habits.

Proficient in a range of frontend technologies, including HTML, CSS, TypeScript, jQuery, React, and more.

Previously served as a full-stack developer, well-versed in backend technologies such as Python, Node.js, MySQL, Django, as well as infrastructures like Docker and Jenkins. Worked in major internet companies, participated in and was independently responsible for multiple projects, with good team communication and collaboration skills, and able to independently complete development tasks according to business needs.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Communication Engineering
University of Electronic Science
and Technology of China
2012-2016
Chengdu,Sichuan,China

SKILLS

Html,Css,Javascript,Typescript,Python, React,Redux,Angular, jQuery,Django,Less, Sass,Antd,MaterialUI,Webpack,Gulp,Mysql, Postgresql,Docker,Jenkins,Cloud platform, Object-Oriented Programming, Team Collaboration,User Experience

Projects

mr-components

2023.12-present https://mr-component.site/ React,Typescript,Material-UI

Shuaibb Photo Management 2023.11-present

React, Typescript, Material-UI, Python, Django, Postgre Sql, Docker

Languages

Chinese(Mandarin)
Native or bilingual proficiency
English
Professional working proficiency

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Front-End Developer

Perfect World Co., Ltd

Jul 2020 - Oct 2023/Beijing, China

- 1. Collaborated with team members to jointly develop the company's internal community app with embedded H5 and game-embedded community.
- 2.Collaborated with the server-side team to develop a fully functional and deliverable CRM system, which increased customer retention and boosted business revenue.
- 3.Extracted and created a library of common business components, reducing boilerplate code within projects, shortening development time and improving the efficiency of the development team.
- 4.Optimized the webpack configuration by utilizing DLL (Dynamic Link Library) to cache third-party libraries and HappyPack for multi-threaded building, which improved the project build speed by nearly 50%.

Full-Stack Engineer

Flow++

Jul 2019 - Jul 2020/Beijing, China

- 1.Developed the Flow series of internal systems for the company using Preact, TypeScript , Node.js, and MySQL.
- 2.Developed Preact-based form validation component (similar to Ant Design's Form) and implemented it within the system, increasing the code development efficiency.
- 3.Set up a private Docker registry for the company and integrated Jenkins for automated deployment in projects, addressing the issue of manual deployment and standardizing the project development process.
- 4.Used rem, media queries, and transform to solve the adaptation problem of the homepage on different devices, especially for large screens.

Front-End Developer

YueshiGuangHe Technology

Aug 2017 - Jun 2019/DaLian, China

- 1.Used technical tools such as HTML5, Less, and Webpack to build the company's official website, and integrated tools like Docker and Jenkins to achieve automated building and deployment.
- 2.Modified HTML files to optimize the company's official website for SEO search increasing website traffic by nearly 70%.
- 3.Used React, Redux, and Ant Design to build and develop a personnel management system. Optimized webpack configuration to reduce bundle size and improve first-screen load speed by nearly 50%.
- 4. Modified the Dockerfile to use a multi-stage build approach, which solved the issue of slow plugin downloads and sped up the build process by nearly 30%.